Guide to the Lance Hidy Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Lance Hidy Collection
1967-1991
AOB 44
Yale University Arts Library
1.5
(5 boxes + 1 broadside drawer)
The Lance Hidy Collection documents the process of book design and illustration through correspondence, proofs, and other ephemera. Of particular note is the documentation of Losing Things at Mr. Mudd's, the first children's picture book to be created on the computer. The collection also contains a good representation of poster designs.
Hidy, Lance, 1946-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lance Hidy.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Lance Hidy '68 works as a graphic designer. His colorful style is widely recognized in posters and books and even a stamp, "Mentoring a Child," for the U.S. Postal Service in 2002. Hidy has worked for a long list of clients, including the Library of Congress, Boston Symphony Orchestra, Children's Memorial Hospital, Chicago, Adobe, and Eastman Kodak, as well as Yale University. Hidy has also taught graphic design at various institutions, including Boston University and the Corcoran School of Art.
Scope and Contents
The Lance Hidy Collection documents the process of book design and illustration through correspondence, proofs, and other ephemera. Of particular note is the documentation of Losing Things at Mr. Mudd's, the first children's picture book to be created on the computer. The collection also contains a good representation of poster designs.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Lance Hidy's Posters: Designs Personal & Public, 1981-1988. II. Losing Things at Mr. Mudd's, 1987-1991. III. Moral Reflections on the Short Life of the Ephemeron, 1967. IV. Other Posters, Proofs, and Prints, 1973-1991. V. Correspondence and Ephemera, 1966-1990.
Graphic design; Book design; Posters; Proofs; Hidy, Lance, 1946-
- Lance Hidy's Posters: Designs Personal & Public, 1981-1988; Series I
  - Book materials, March 20, 1983 undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue correspondence, February-October 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between Godine, Hidy and Fern, October 19, 1981-April 11, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Hidy to Gay Walker, August 23, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Essay drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mechanicals, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mechanicals, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photostats, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Poster book promotion, November 1983 undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poster captions, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Preliminary text, etc., June 7, 1983 undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Publicity for book, 1983 undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Repros, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Xerox of corrected Van Dykes, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Xerox of corrected Van Dykes, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Losing Things at Mr. Mudd's, 1987-1991; Series II
  - Correspondence, page layouts, etc., 1991 undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence regarding dust jacket, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Drawings for illustrations, 1987 undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Drawings for illustrations, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Drawings for illustrations, story board, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Drawings, computer composites, photocopy of book, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Drawings, proofs, story board, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Photocopies of book, January 14, 1990 undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Photocopies of book and illustrations, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Photocopies of book and illustrations, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Photocopies of book with comments, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Photographs taken for illustrations, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Proofs for illustrations, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Proofs for illustrations, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Proofs for illustrations, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Slides of photos for book, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Slides of photos for book, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Story line with comments, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Negatives of book pages (4 pages), undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Negatives of illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Photocopies of book and illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Photocopies of book with comments, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Proofs for illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Proofs for illustrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Moral Reflections on the Short Life of the Ephemeron, 1967; Series III
  - Loose pages of book, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Other Posters, Proofs, and Prints, 1973-1991; Series IV
  - Posters
    - American Foundation for Surgery of the Hand, 1990 (Folder 1)
    - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1985 (Folder 1)
    - ASPO/Lamaze, 1985 (Folder 1)
    - Beardsley's Café Restaurant, undated (Folder 1)
    - Black Oak Books, 1985 (Folder 1)
    - Boarding House and Boise, 1981 (Folder 1)
    - Boston Public Library, 1991 (Folder 1)
    - Center for Creative Imaging, 1991 (Folder 1)
    - Columbia University School of Library Service, 1987 (Folder 1)
    - David R. Godine, Publisher, 1982 (Folder 1)
    - Dow and Frosini, Framing Posters & Prints, 1979 (Folder 1)
    - Firehouse Center for the Arts, 1986 (Folder 1)
    - Flora Lamson Hewlett Library of the Graduate Theological Union, 1987 (Folder 1)
    - Godine Press, 1973 (Folder 1)
    - Lance Hidy Electric Art, November 15, 1990 (Folder 1)
    - Lance Hidy's Designs Personal and Public, 1983 (Folder 1)
    - League of New Hampshire Craftsmen Jubilee, 1981 (Folder 1)
    - Meriden Gravure Company, 1983 (Folder 1)
    - Stinehour Press, 1983 (Folder 1)
    - Vintage Books the Library of America, 1990 (Folder 1)
    - Weathervane Theatre, 1981 (Folder 1)
    - White Mountains Festival '80, 1980 (Folder 1)
    - Yale University Sterling Memorial Library, undated (Folder 1)
    - Unidentified, 1985 (Folder 1)
  - Proofs
    - ASPO/Lamaze, undated (Folder 1)
    - Boston Public Library, undated (Folder 1)
    - David R. Godine, Publisher, 1980 (Folder 1)
    - Meriden-Stinehour, undated (Folder 1)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1)
  - Prints
    - Angelo Pellegrini, undated (Folder 1)
    - Unidentified, 1982 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence and Ephemera, 1966-1990
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains additional graphic works by Hidy, including examples of printed ephemera executed while Hidy was a student in Jonathan Edwards College at Yale University. The series also contains some correspondence written by Hidy.
  - Various printed ephemera, including concert programs for Jonathan Edwards College, etc., 1966-1970 undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Various printed ephemera, including concert programs for Jonathan Edwards College, "Assurances" by Walt Whitman, "We are all brothers," and "Season's Greetings 1966" envelope and booklet for Boise Cascade Corporation, etc., 1966-1971 undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    This folder also contains correspondence from Hidy to Dale Roylance, Curator of the Graphic Arts Collection at Sterling Memorial Library, as well as two small maquettes for Moral Reflections on the Short Life of the Ephemeron and for A Free-Thinker by Bishop Pearce.
  - Various printed ephemera, including concert programs, a menu, and other jobs printed for Jonathan Edwards College, 1966-1971 undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    This folder also contains correspondence from Hidy to Dale Roylance.
  - Promotional materials for Lance Hidy's Posters: Designs Personal & Public, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Promotional materials for Lance Hidy's Posters: Designs Personal & Public, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    This folder contains two fliers for "The Return of the Poster," a slide lecture given by Lance Hidy at the Boston Public Library, December 6, 1983.
  - [Six Months - Hidy] Various printed ephemera, including bookplates, graphic works for Jonathan Edwards College, etc., 1966-1983 undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    This folder also contains the following: photocopies of newspaper clippings about Hidy's work; promotional materials for Lance Hidy's Posters; and proofs and original sketches for "The Mayfly" as well as the May 1967 issue of The Yale Literary Magazine that featured "The Mayfly" by Lance Hidy.
  - Promotional materials for Lance Hidy's Posters: Designs Personal & Public, 1987 undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Various printed ephemera, including graphic works for Jonathan Edwards College and promotional materials for Lance Hidy's Posters: Designs Personal & Public, 1967 1983 undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - [The Hon. Alan Boyle's Wrecked Avis Monoplane at Bournemouth July, 1910]., undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - [Exhibition checklist for "Lance Hidy: Designs Personal and Public" at the Albin O. Kuhn Library and Gallery, August 25-October 28, 1983.] (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - [Memorial keepsake for Glenn Dale Hogan (1934-1982)]., April 11, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - [Yale Summer 1988] booklet featuring Lance Hidy cover design. (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - [Invitation to "Electric Design," a talk given by Lance Hidy for The Society of Printers on April 4, 1990]. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - [The Hon. Desmond Guinness will give an illustrated lecture on Irish Houses & Castles of the 18th Century, Jonathan Edwards College, Tuesday, Oct. 24, 8:30 p.m. in the Great Hall]., undated (Box 5, Folder 54)